Daniel Sokolov

Fair Lawn, NJ 551 250 7028 ◆ <u>sokolovd.work@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielsokolov/

Profile:

In-depth knowledge of .NET framework, Relational and Document databases (MS SQL, MongoDB). Strong OOP\OOD skills, experience with design patterns. Puts DDD and CQRS concepts to practice. Takes pride in finding elegant solutions, reducing code duplication and improving code readability. Self-starter, able to take concepts to final stages with minimal supervision.

Professional Experience:

Apr 2019-Current Software Engineer

Point 72

Backend SW engineer for a web based data hub application developed by Market Intelligence group. Application combines data from various sources and provides valuable insights to traders and business analysts.

- Performed code reviews, pushed to eliminate code duplication, engaged team discussions about existing pain points and long term vision.
- Introduced code quality and coverage metrics by integrating SonarQube and OpenCover into Jenkins deployment pipeline.
- Presented DDD concepts to the team. Pushed for using rich over anemic models. Explained how rich models and proper encapsulation can reduce a surface for future errors.
- Designed custom content management solution (item level permissions). Convinced product team to change initial design and follow Google Docs sharing model.
- Added Bloomberg as a provider for the company's financial calendar. Extracted, simplified and made testable the ranking logic of incoming data. Covered new logic with unit tests providing confidence for future modifications.
- Designed and implemented SEC Filings documents import workflow from 3rd party provider (Refinitiv). Used DataFlow to provide robust and scalable processing. Significantly simplified existing stages of the workflow by removing duplication and unnecessary complexity.
- Developed Web API to fetch user data from One Note. Used OAuth 2.0 authorization grant flow to securely call Azure Resource Graph API.

Technologies: C#, Web Api, MongoDb, ElasticSearch, Azure

Jul 2016-Apr 2019 Lead Product Engineer

ACA Technology

IMS is a portfolio management application that supports various aspects of trading activity. It provides near real time updates on users activity, supports a large set of investment types, provides compliance and allocation engines and warehouse reporting. WinForms Client is interacting with WCF services using proprietary message bus built on top of ZeroMQ and using protobuf serialization.

- Hands on technical lead. Drives design and implementation of core product features.
- Managed tasks, provided technical guidance and mentorship for a team of 4 developers.
- Simplified implementation of tax lot calculation engine by extracting common functionality into dedicated classes later used as building blocks.
- Implemented PnL calculations for non locally funded positions.
- Enhanced tax lots engine to support Fund of Funds (allocators) investment types.
- Reduced application memory footprint (up to 40% on start up) by lazily loading securities.
- Worked with PM to come up with business scenarios and financial calculations needed to implement a trading form for repurchase agreements (Repos).

Technologies: C#, MultiThreading, WCF, StructureMap, Protobuf, PostSharp, Sql Server 2012.

Dec 2013-Jul 2016 Application Developer

State Street

truView is a web based portfolio management and risk analytics platform.

Improving performance and stability of the analytic calculations engine. Development of new features.

- Implemented Reallocation feature creation of virtual portfolio where existing positions are weighted differently.
- Applied system wide refactoring to support multiple views (category/permission based) while reducing the total amount of code.
- Lowered application startup time by identifying and resolving a performance issue where multiple calls were made for the same data as a result of incorrect initialization logic.
- Refactored and extended export functionality to support PDF format. Applied inversion of control
 principle to expose hidden dependencies, reduce usage of global state (static methods) and improve
 testability.
- Initiated coding style discussions in the team.

Technologies: C#, WCF, ASP.Net MVC 3.0, Ext Js 4.0, Sql Server 2008.

Aug 2010-Oct 2013 Software Engineer

Cellebrite

- Maintained and developed a content management application for mobile devices.
- Took active part in design and implementation decisions for the new features.
- Pioneered the use of TDD techniques for new developments.

Technologies: C#, WinForms, C++\CLI

Nov 2007-Aug 2010 Software Engineer, SharePoint Consultant Websio

- Hands-on experience on practically every aspect of SharePoint development and administration.
- Interacted with stakeholders to gather requirements.

Technologies: SharePoint 2007, Asp.Net, Web Services, C#(.Net 2.0, 3.5), SQL server 2008.

May 2005-Nov 2007 Software Engineer

Omnisys

• Web and SharePoint development

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, SharePoint 2003, BizTalk 2006, InfoPath

Education:

Feb 2001 - Jun 2005 Technion - Israeli Institute of Technology Haifa, Israel BSc in Industrial Engineering and Management (Major: Informational Systems)

Web Presence:

PluralSight: https://app.pluralsight.com/profile/daniel-sokolov
Stack Overflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/1453989/daniels